Hello everyone, I hope you doing well.
Today I would like to present my
project about creating a master
slave distributed architecture.
So before getting into details
I want to introduce the subject. We all
know know that big
companies like Instagram or
Facebook might have millions
or even billions of users every day.
The question appears here. How does
this companies handle all this traffic?
It is impossible to using just
one server to handle all this traffic. So
we have to use multiple servers to be
capable of handling the
huge traffic commands from the user.
So that is the idea about my
project is to demonstrate how
can we use multiple services.
Or multiple servers
handle the requests coming from
the
further ado, let's get started.
this phase, the master should decide
which slave should perform the
mathematical calculation. So
the master will send the request firstly
to the first slave and ask him a binary
question. Are you available to perform
this task?So the slave will will
response will response either I'm
available or I am not available. So the
master in the case. When the
slave is available, the master will
assign the will assign the task to the
first slave and the slave starts
performing for calculating the
mathematical expression. So let's assume
in this case that this mathematical
expression will take 7 seconds
and in this phase there
is a calculation that's
performing here. So the client
will send another request with another
another mathematical expression. The
master will ask the first slave if it's
available. Sure the the
response it should be I'm not available.
So the master will ask
will ask the second slave. The second
slave response I am available. The master
will assign the second the second
mathematical expression to the second
slave. So the slave 2 will start
performing the the
expression and now it assumes
again that the clients will send
another request or another request to the
master. The master master of course
will assign will assign the
mathematical expression to the third
slave and now we we
have the server is busy. So
when clients again send a request
to perform another mathematical
expression, the master will response
will response which I am busy enough. So
when the slave get when the
task with the task being
completed in the first slave, the slave
will send will send the result to the
master. The masters should save the task
thus the result in the task list.
So the client to know what is the result
of the task, it should
send the request to the master to get the
list of the result of the tasks.
And that's what's happening in the
architecture and
now let's go to the technical
explain.
So the first step to do is to
open in Hyper-V and setting up three
machines, one master and two slaves
Now let's go to the postman to check our
code. So if I send a request to the
gate slaves, OK, you see here there
are two slaves registered now
Submit a new task. I want to perform this
operation. So if I send the request, it
say that the task is assigned to this
slave. Go into the get task. How can you
see the second slave is busy now
if I get task or the
status now is done. So
thank you very much for watchingAnd I
hope you like the topic.